#### Mauricio Meirelles

mobile: +55 51 91997345 mail: mauricio.m@gmail.com

# Summary

I have been a software engineer over the last 10+ years, but it in 2009 that I found my true passion. I live iOS since 2009, I love developing apps for fun and also to enhance the user's life and I love spreading the word by teaching developers how to create awesome apps.

# Experience

### iOS Instructor @ Instituto de Pesquisas Eldorado

June 2013 - Present - Porto Alegre/RS, Brazil

Instructor at BEPiD (Brazilian Education Program for iOS Development), a pioneering program with support from Apple. My role is to teach iOS to university students in an one year course that should prepare them to start their own startups and develop great apps.

### Lead iOS Developer/Co-Founder @ Beelieve

August 2009 - Present - Porto Alegre/RS, Brazil

Co-Founder of Beelieve, startup focused on iOS development. Here are some examples of Apps that we developed, <u>click on them</u> to find out more:

- Journo News Nearby!
- BeHere
- Chubby Chicken Game
- Jack The Bunny Game
- Laika Game
- Game Coder
- Pinosoccer

## iOS Developer @ Grupo RBS

October 2012 - May 2013 (8 months) - Porto Alegre/RS, Brazil

Develop iOS Apps for Grupo RBS (Brazilian media conglomerate, is one of Brazil's largest communication groups). Follow some examples of apps that I developed, special mention to Zero Hora app for iPad/iPhone. Zero Hora is a Brazilian newspaper based in the city of Porto Alegre, the seventh biggest of the country, <u>click on them</u> to find out more:

- Zero Hora
- Gremista ZH
- Colorado ZH
- Diario Catarinense

## Oracle EBS Consultant @ Instituto de Pesquisas Eldorado (working for Dell)

April 2011 – August 2011 (5 months) - Porto Alegre/RS, Brazil

Oracle EBS Consultant developing enhancements and new projects at Dell. Working with MO and a Global Environment.

### Oracle EBS Functional Consultant - P2P (PO/AP) @ HCL Tech

September 2009 – April 2011 (1 year 8 months) - São Leopoldo/RS, Brazil

Oracle EBS Consultant in P2P (PO/AP/iSupplier/iExpense/RI/Sourcing)

Clients: Renner, Procergs, Ricardo Eletro, Energia Sustentável.

#### Software Developer @ Dell Inc

October 2005 - September 2009 (3 years 11 months) - Porto Alegre/RS, Brazil | Austin/TX - US

I worked at US DOMS team, developing new code, maintaining the legacy and attending support level 3. I traveled several times to Austin to requirement gathering and helped on developing a new tool to facilitate the impact analyse of a new requirement in the US DOMS modules. Rated two times as an Excellent employee, won a Bronze prize as an Individual and a Silver and a Gold prizes as a team.

### Education

Bachelor of Information Systems (BIS)

PUCRS (Brazil), 2007

Graduate Student of Business Management with Oracle EBS

PUCRS (Brazil), 2012

### **Publications**

#### iOS Development in Swift

iTunes U

"iOS Development in Swift" is a free course available in iTunes U. It covers a lot of topics around iOS Development using the new language release by Apple, Swift.

# Training and Events

Apple WWDC15

June 2015

Apple WWDC14

June 2014

iOS Programming @ Big Nerd Ranch

September 2013

Apple WWDC13

June 2013

iOS Programming @ Treinamentos.mobi

June 2012

iOS 5 Tech Talk World Tour 2011 - São Paulo

January 2012